那些你闻所未闻的骇人神话生物
Horrifying mythical creatures that you've never heard of.
要说这世间的故事，恐怕很少有比东南亚的奇闻异兽更惊悚的了
Seldom would you find tales of critters and creatures more terrifying than those from Southeast Asia.
那些地方简直就是噩梦燃料驱动的柴油机
Places like the Diesel of Nightmare Fuel.
首先登场的是庞蒂雅娜，一个满腔怨气的恶灵
First up is the Pontianak, a malevolent spirit with a bone to pick.
尤其对你的骨头，那二百零六块，全都虎视眈眈
Specifically yours. All 206 of them.
这个传说起源于马来西亚和印度尼西亚的民间故事
Originating from the likes of Malaysian and Indonesian folklore,
据说庞蒂雅娜是一位孕妇的复仇之魂
the Pontianak is said to be the vengeful spirit of a pregnant woman who
她或死于分娩，或死于伴侣之手
either died in childbirth or at the hands of her partner.
想象一下，你正在马来西亚的午夜漫步，喝着一碗马来西亚风味的马来汤*
So imagine that you're taking a midnight Malaysian stroll, slurping down a Malaysian meal of Malaysian soup.
*马来汤也就是叻沙
在沸腾高汤和蒸腾蔬菜的香气中，你的鼻子捕捉到一丝淡淡的花香
Through the aroma of boiling broth and steamy veggies, your nose catches the subtle scent of flowers.
你的耳朵，则听到了婴儿微弱的啼哭
Your ears, the delicate cry of an infant.
就在那时，你瞥见黑暗中一个身影
It's just then that you spot a figure in the dark,
站在一棵高大、华美、果实累累的香蕉树下
standing beneath a big, beautiful, bountiful banana tree.
一位年轻女子优雅地步入月光，身着飘逸的白裙，一头丝滑的乌黑长发
Gracefully creeping into the moonlight is a young woman, clad in a flowing white dress with silky, long, raven black hair.
还有那要命的傲人身姿
And friggin sweet honkers.
但那正是她们的圈套
But that's how they get you.
诱惑是庞蒂雅娜最擅长的武器
Seduction is the Pontianak's weapon of choice.
至少在最初的引诱阶段是这样
At least for the initial bait.
不过只要你是个正人君子，就没什么好怕的
But as long as you're a nice guy, you should have nothing to fear.
当然不是网络上定义的那种“老好人”
And not the reddit definition of a nice guy.
负心汉、家暴男，还有英雄联盟玩家
Cheaters, beaters, and legend leaguers
要是撞上庞蒂雅娜，都将面临可怕的命运
all face a terrible fate should they cross the path of a Pontianak.
所以要接近她，风险自负
So approach at your own risk.
如果你真被那股子男人气概冲昏了头，想在半夜三更搭讪一个女鬼
If you do find yourself overcome with the manly urge to try to pick up a ghostly gal in the middle of the night,
在你采取行动时，会注意到一些异样
you'll notice a few things as you make your move.
其一，那宜人的花香很快会变成纯粹的腐臭
For one, that delightful floral scent quickly turns to pure putrescence.
她那柔软苍白的手，此刻长出了剃刀般锋利的指甲
Her soft pale hands now don razor sharp nails.
而她那娇美的脸庞，也露出了嗜血的獠牙
And her delicate face now bears bloodthirsty fangs.
你将面临一场恶战
You're in for a rough encounter.
庞蒂雅娜的攻击方式是纯粹物理攻击，所以保持距离本是明智之举
The Pontianak has a purely physical attack style, so keeping your distance would have been wise.
如果你从她恐怖外表的惊吓中幸存下来
If you survive the shock of her terrifying appearance,
你很快就会希望自己还是死了算了
you're gonna wish that you hadn't,
因为你全身的痛觉感受器将会开始尖叫
as all of your pain receptors will now be the ones screaming.
说到尖叫，庞蒂雅娜可能会发出一声震耳欲聋的哀嚎，足以震破你的耳膜
Speaking of which, a Pontianak may choose to let out a deafening wail capable of rupturing your eardrums.
但耳朵流血只是小事，因为很快你的肚子也要开花了
But bleeding ears are the least of your worries, cause soon you'll have a bleeding belly.
作为对她未能出生的孩子的象征性补偿
As a symbolic gesture for the child that she was never able to bear,
庞蒂雅娜会用她那可怕的爪子
a Pontianak will take her terrifying talons
刺穿你颤抖的肚皮，偷走你的胃，掠夺你的肝，再绑架你的肾
and tear through your trembling tummy, stealing your stomach, looting your liver, and kidnapping your kidneys.
为什么？因为它们味道不错
Why? Because they taste good.
但如果你不想自己的五脏六腑被翻个底朝天，可以试试这么做
But if you don't feel like having your insides being converted to outsides, here's what you can do.
首先，也是最明显的，别在半夜三更去接近哭泣的女人
First and most obvious, don't approach crying women in the middle of the night.
这是个巨大的危险信号，赶紧走开，那是别人的麻烦
It's a huge red flag. Walk on. That's someone else's problem.
其次，瞥一眼她的玉足
Second, take a glance down at her piggies.
传说庞蒂雅娜的脚很丑，这可能是一个让你赶紧溜之大吉的警示
Legends state that Pontianaks have gross feet, so this may be a warning sign to hightail it out of there.
当然也可能她只是脚长得丑
Or she might just have gross feet.
第三个选择，虽然有点破费，是庞蒂雅娜据说讨厌炮火的轰鸣声
As a third option, albeit a bit expensive, is that Pontianaks apparently hate the sound of cannon blasts.
所以如果你身陷险境，让她尝尝炮管的滋味
So if you're facing peril, have her stare down a barrel.
第四，最后，也最有效的方法是，如果你发现自己快被撕成碎片了
Fourth, final, and most effective if you find yourself about to be shredded to bits,
设法绕到这个幽灵背后，用一根铁钉插进她的后颈
is managing to get behind the spooky spirit and jamming an iron nail into the nape of her neck.
这是庞蒂雅娜的出厂重置按钮
This is the Pontianaks factory reset spot,
能让她变得温顺、驯服，而且根据某些离奇的传说版本
rendering her docile, subdued, and apparently according to some strange versions of the legend,
她会成为所谓的“大和抚子”
she will become quote-unquote, the perfect wife.
至少，在钉子被拔掉之前是这样
At least, until the nail is removed.
之后她又会故态复萌，重操杀戮旧业
Then she just gets back to her murderous ways.
老兄，快跑啊，那个庞蒂雅娜见人就追
Dude, you gotta run! That Pontianak is after everybody!
可我正听得起劲呢
But I'm jammin'.
那边那个恶魔马上就要把她的爪子插进你肚子了，你最好……
Well that demon over there is about to jam her fangers into your belly, so you better-
前方丝滑小连招，请空降……别空降了，挺有意思的，看完吧
你戴的什么
What are those?
我的 Raycon 耳机
My Raycons.
本视频由 Raycon 赞助播出
This video is sponsored by Raycon.
这是 Raycon 的 Everyday Earbuds Classic
These are Raycon's Everyday Earbuds Classic.
你每天都会戴着的经典款耳塞
Those classic earbuds you'll be wearing every day.
受够了那些像橡皮泥一样把你头骨挤变形的笨重耳机吗
Sick of those bulky headphones that morph your skull like Play-Doh?
厌倦了那些只要你稍微一动就会从耳朵里掉出来的耳塞吗
Tired of earbuds that fall out of your ear holes the microsecond you engage in any kind of physical activity?
不想为那些定价过高的破烂货付掉你四分之一的房租吗
Don't want to fork over a quarter of your rent for overpriced nonsense?
Raycon 正是你的救星
That's where Raycon's got your back.
我自己已经用了好几个月了，可以坦白地说，这是一款非常扎实的产品
I've been using my own for several months now and can honestly say that they're a solid product.
无论我是在户外经受风雨，还是在室内进行日常锻炼
Whether I'm weathering the weather outside or doing my daily domicile drills inside,
Raycon 的人体工学设计和32小时的电池续航，确保我永远不必停下
Raycon's ergonomic fit and 32 hours of battery life ensure that I don't ever need to stop.
如果我急需用电，只需快充10分钟，就能获得90分钟的播放时间
But if I am in a pinch, just a quick 10 minute charge will give me 90 minutes of play time.
想在月下起舞时，也知晓周遭动静吗
Want to know what's going on while you're dancing in the moonlight?
它的感知模式让你在尽情摇摆的同时，也能保持高度警惕
Awareness mode keeps you on high alert while you're still able to get low.
需要在办公室集中精神吗
Need to lock in at the office?
Raycon 时尚小巧的设计，意味着你可以随身携带
Raycon's sleek and small design means that you can bring it anywhere.
放进口袋，带上火箭，塞进袜子，只要你装得下
In your pocket, on a rocket, in your sock if you can stock it.
Everyday Earbuds Classic 有多种颜色可选，以搭配你的个人风格
The Everyday Earbuds Classic are available in several colors to match your aesthetic.
如果这听起来很不错，就点击下方置顶评论里的链接
So if that sounds pretty neat, click and finger my link in the pinned comment below
或者访问 buyraycon.com/chathistory
or go to buyraycon.com/chathistory
购买属于你的 Everyday Earbuds，即可享受八折优惠
to get 20% off of your own pair of everyday earbuds.
好吧，庞蒂雅娜，我可不怕你
All right, Ponchi Neck. I ain't scared of you.
我勒个……
Oh, fu-
现在我们从东南亚跳到西非的森林，去会会萨萨邦萨姆
Now we jump ship from Southeast Asia to the forests of West Africa with the Sasabonsam.
作为跳杀的鼻祖，这个狡猾的小恶魔，潜伏在加纳的森林冠层之中
The OG jump scarer, this slippery little devil, hides in the canopies of the forests of Ghana,
等待着下一个受害者在林间徘徊
waiting for its next victim to wander through the woods.
据说这种生物体型巨大，远超常人
The beings are said to be huge, much larger than an average human,
它的巨颚能一口吞下整颗头颅
with jaws capable of swallowing ahead a hole in one gulp.
尽管比例奇特，萨萨邦萨姆的外形却像猿猴，四肢修长摇摆
Although oddly proportioned, the Sasabonsam is ape-like in appearance with gangly, dangly arms and legs,
躯干纤细，通常被描绘成深色或红色的皮毛
and a slender torso, often depicted with dark or red-colored fur.
它用铁钩般的脚爪紧紧抓住加纳的树木
Using its iron-hooked feet to grip a grasp on Ghanaian growth,
小萨潜伏在树上，等待猎物
the Sasabonsam lurks in the trees, awaiting its prey.
一旦发现目标，这个怪物就会兴奋地扭动手指
Once spotted, the monster will wiggle its fingies in delight with a
带着一种“不吃白不吃”的态度
don't-mind-if-I-do attitude
就像要从便利店保温柜里抓起最后一根热狗
like it's about to grab the last hot dog out of the warm Wawa hot dog cabinet.
为了捕杀，小萨会在树枝间摇荡
Going in for the kill, the Sasabonsam swings from the tree limbs
趁那些深夜里毫无防备的独行旅客不备，一把将他们攫走
to snatch and grab any would-be traveler, should they be caught unawares, alone, in the dead of night.
怪物那巨硕的手臂会将你禁锢在致命的拥抱中，碾碎你的骨骼和内脏
The monster's monstrous arms envelop you in a deadly death hug, crushing your bones and internals.
幸运的是，这很可能在它享用你的遗体之前，就先送你魂归地府了
Luckily, this will most likely send you to the shadow realm before it ever gets a chance to feed on your remains.
如果你是个比较谨慎的人
If you are more of a cautious individual,
小萨可能会试图用它模仿熟悉声音的能力
the Sasabonsam may attempt to disarm or disorient you
来解除你的戒心或让你迷失方向
with its ability to mimic familiar sounds.
那是什么声音
What was that?
一旦你偏离了正轨，你的预期寿命会骤降至几秒
Once you've been thrown off course, your life expectancy quickly drops to mere seconds
因为一个荡来荡去的吸血猴人正准备下手
as a swinging vampire monkey man makes its move.
但如果你不想成为猴人的盘中餐，还是有预防措施可以采取的
But if you don't want to end up a monkey man's meal, there are precautions that you can take.
其一，千万不要在晚上独自在森林里行走，这是这个传说的核心教训
For one, never travel alone in the forest at night. It's kind of the takeaway lesson for this legend.
与同伴一起旅行，可以避免不测，还能聊聊天
Travel with a companion to avoid an untimely demise and to spark good conversation.
然后我跟那家伙说，三明治里别放番茄
And I told the guy, no tomato on the sandwich.
结果他干了什么，他给我加了双份的番茄，这简直太离谱了
And what does he do? He puts extra tomatoes on it. I mean, that's just ridiculous.
你他妈给我闭嘴
此外，据说由你们村里牧师祝福过的护身符
Additionally, protective charms blessed by your local village priest
可以驱赶这种生物，因为它们讨厌宗教的味道
are said to ward off the creatures as they hate the taste of religion.
但如果这些简单的办法都行不通，也别担心
But if these simple solutions just don't seem possible, don't worry.
因为另一个解决方案已在酝酿之中，你可以感谢巧克力
For another solution is already in the making, and you can think chocolate.
在你尴尬地向这野兽递上一块巧克力之前，请听我解释
Now, before you embarrassingly offer a bar to the beast, let me explain.
你看，小萨靠树木为生，那我们干脆把树都砍了
You see, Sasabonsam thrive in the trees, so let's just get rid of the trees.
由于可可的过度种植
Thanks to excessive cocoa farming,
加纳自1950年代以来，已经失去了大部分的原始森林
Ghana has lost a majority of its primary forest since the 1950s.
诚然，树是没了，但这个虚构的怪物不也跟着没了吗
Sure, the trees are gone, but so is this fictitious freak.
戴上耳罩吧，因为下一个出场的怪物，是个真正的尖叫高手
Strap on some earmuffs, cause this next creature's a real screecher.
从南斯拉夫民间传说中爬出来的，是 Drekavac，意为“尖叫者”
Slopped out of southern Slavic folklore is the Drekavac, which translates to the screamer.
这个神话在不同版本的故事中有多种形态
This myth takes on many forms across several different variations of its story.
但在本视频中，我们将采用它的婴儿形态
But for this video, we will go with its infant form.
Drekavac 据说是一个未受洗礼的孩子的不宁之魂，渴望得到救赎
The Drekavac is said to be the restless spirit of an unbaptized child, desperate for salvation.
根据传说，Drekavac 的形态是一个灰色、骨瘦如柴的幼儿
According to legend, the Drekavac takes the form of a gray, emaciated young child.
它身形孱弱，四肢细长，唯一不成比例的是它那颗硕大无比的脑袋
Little limber limbs accompany its frail stature, offset only by its monstrously large dome,
这脑袋降临人世时，想必是摧毁了一条产道
which definitely devastated a birth canal upon entry into this world.
它们在圣诞节前后最为猖獗，肯定会给任何人的节庆蒙上阴影
They are most prevalent around Christmas time, sure to put a damper on anyone's festivities.
但它们绝对不会被忽视
But they certainly will not go unnoticed.
问题是，只要看一眼这个小家伙，你就会忍不住说
Problem is, one glance at this little fellow will make you go,
呃
Ugh.
它那凸出、呆滞的黑眼睛里，空无一物
Not a thought exists behind its bulging glassy black eyes.
没有思想，只有死亡
No thought, but death.
如果它的名字还不够明显，Drekavac 能发出刺破耳膜的尖叫
If it wasn't obvious by its name, the Drekavac is capable of emitting eardrum rupturing shrieks,
一声尖啸就能让你跪倒在地
able to bring you to your knees in a single squeal.
没错，就像那样
Yeah, like that.
Drekavac 本身并不会立刻把你变成一滩新鲜的番茄酱
Now the Drekavac itself is not an immediate threat in terms of it wanting to convert you into a fresh marinara.
相反，它是一个若隐若现的凶兆
Instead, it serves as a looming omen.
据说，那些发现自己身处其阴影之下的人，注定在未来几天内惨死
It is said that those who find themselves in its shadow are doomed to die a terrible death in the coming days.
如果发现它在附近，整个村庄都可能遭遇不幸
Whole villages may suffer cruel fates should they spot one nearby.
这个传说本身常被用作对幼儿的威慑
The legend itself is often used as a deterrent for young children,
教导他们不要离家太远，以免与这个小恶魔不期而遇
teaching them to not wander too far from home lest they cross paths with the diminutive demon.
夜晚当地野生动物发出的奇怪嚎叫
Strange howls or yells in the night from local wildlife
也常被归咎于 Drekavac，以此向受惊的孩子们证明它的存在
are often attributed to the Drekavac as a way to prove their existence to traumatized children.
我的意思是，我们中有些人被告知，每年会有一只巨大的人形兔子
I mean, some of us were told that a giant anthropomorphic rabbit breaks into our houses
闯入我们家，留下糖果作为好行为的交换
once a year to leave us candy offerings in exchange for good behavior.
所以，这真的有那么牵强吗
So, is it really that far-fetched?
父母为了让孩子听话，什么事都做得出来，不是吗
Parents do a lot to make sure that their kids behave, don't they?
老实说，我迫不及待地想有一天告诉我的小Chat
Honestly, I can't wait to tell Little Chat
一个小仙女会从他的窗户闯进来，用几块钱换走他掉的牙齿
one day about how a small fairy will break in through his window to steal his dead teeth in exchange for a few bucks.
不过，和大多数生物一样，Drekavac 也是可以被击败的
Well, like most critters, the Drekavac can be defeated.
最直接的方法，是为这个孩子举行适当的洗礼，最终让它的灵魂得到安息
The most obvious method is having the child properly baptized, finally putting its soul to rest.
所以，只需让你友好的邻家牧师加入队伍，对着它那不洁的屁股施放圣光术
So, just have your friendly neighborhood priest join the party and cast holy on its unholy ass.
或者，你知道的，往它脸上泼一杯圣水
Or, you know, splash a cup of holy water in its face.
啊
Ah!
安息吧
Rest in peace.
啊，日本的民间传说
Ah, Japanese folklore.
在给孩子和成人灌输恐惧方面，他们绝对是非常有创造力的文化
Definitely a very creative culture for instilling fear into kids and adults alike.
毕竟，我们需要用一些更……可怕的东西来平衡那些可爱的动漫女孩
After all, we need to balance the uwu anime girls with something a bit more...fearsome.
爬行妖怪正是如此
The Techie Techie does just that.
这个诞生于悲剧的恐怖恶鬼，源于一个年轻女子或女学生
Born from tragedy, this ghastly ghoul is the result of a young woman or schoolgirl
她掉落或被推到铁轨上，没能及时躲开
who had fallen or was pushed onto train tracks and failed to get out of the way in time,
导致她的体重减轻了50%，但愤怒值增加了100%
causing her to become 50% lighter, but 100% angrier.
我更倾向于那个被恶意推下去的故事，因为自己掉到铁轨上纯属活该
I prefer the story of it being a malicious push, as simply just falling onto the train tracks is your own fault.
各位，请时刻站在黄线后面
Stay behind the yellow line at all times, people.
作为一个复仇的怨灵，爬行妖怪是一个暴力的小妖女
Being a vengeful spirit, or Anria, the Techie Techie is a violent little vixen,
旨在猎杀那些在深夜里于废弃地点或铁轨附近游荡的活人
aiming to hunt down the living who wander around deserted locations or train tracks in the middle of the night.
她的存在完全是一个警示故事，劝诫孩子们不要在深夜去那些地方探险
Her existence serves solely as a cautionary tale for kids, discouraging any late-night adventures to such places.
父母为了保护孩子而编造的故事，真是有趣
It's interesting the tales that parents come up with to protect their children.
所以，对话不是这样的……
So instead of it being like...
好了，爸，我要和朋友去那个废弃的旧工厂了
Alright Dad, I'm going to that old abandoned factory with some friends.
你倒是敢去，那地方不安全
The hell you are, that place isn't safe.
而是这样的……
It's more like...
好了，爸，我要和朋友去那个废弃的旧工厂了
Alright Dad, I'm going to that old abandoned factory with some friends.
当然，没问题，只是要小心别被……
Sure, no problem. Just make sure you don't get murdered by...
“工厂掏肠手”给杀了
The Factory Fingerer.
什么
What?
任何与爬行妖怪的相遇，都可能是你的最后一次
Any encounter with a Techie Techie could be your last.
虽然她只是一个年轻女孩的半身幻影
While they are just a half-body apparition of a young girl,
她们依然是不可小觑的力量
they're still a force to be reckoned with.
你或许首先会通过她双手拍打水泥地的声音察觉到她的到来
You may first become aware of its arrival by the sound of its hands slapping on the cement,
这是她的行走方式，也是她拟声名字的由来
which is how it walks, and the origin of its onomatopoeic name.
在某些版本的故事里，她手持一把小镰刀作为武器
In some tellings of the story, she carries a small scythe as a weapon.
另一些版本里，她长着剃刀般锋利的指甲
Others, she bears razor-sharp nails.
如果她靠近你，她可能会问你一个简单的问题
If approached, she may ask you a simple question.
我的腿在哪里
Where are my legs?
当然，是用日语问
In Japanese, of course.
这是一个陷阱问题
This is a trick question.
她可没有腿，丹中尉
She ain't got no legs, Lieutenant Dan.
不过，如果你看到一个内脏外露的女鬼用手向你爬来
Though, if you see a ghostly gal with her insides spilling out lumbering towards you on her hands,
常识应该告诉你，要立刻掉头就跑
it should be common sense that you 180 the hell out of there.
但是，你错了
But, you'd be wrong.
虽然她只能用手臂移动，但据说她速度极快
Although she is restricted to just arms for movement, she is noted to be incredibly fast,
如有必要，甚至能追上汽车
even able to catch up to cars if necessary.
一旦她抓住你，她会让你也尝尝她自己的命运
Once she gets a hold of you, she will treat you to a similar fate as her own,
用她的镰刀或指甲，像开足球周末的啤酒罐一样，把你劈成两半
using her scythe or nails to crack you open like a football Sunday beer can.
根据传说，不幸的是，没有明确的方法可以打败她
Now, according to legend, and unfortunately for you, there's no clear way to defeat her,
主要是听从传说的警告，避开废弃地区和铁轨
mainly just heeding the tale's warning to avoid deserted areas and train tracks.
不过，我敢肯定，一脚45码的射门应该能搞定她
However, I'm sure a solid 45-yard field goal attempt could get the job done.
有什么比骷髅更可怕，一个会飞的巨型头骨
What's scarier than a skeleton? A giant skull that flies.
它起源于易洛魁或豪德诺索尼美洲原住民的民间传说
Originating from the folklore of the Iroquois or Haudenosaunee Native Americans
流传于纽约州北部的萨坎达加湖周边
surrounding the Great Sacandaga Lake in upstate New York,
这个巨大的骷髅怪物是噩梦的化身
this sizable skull monster is the stuff of nightmares.
它被称为 Kanontsistonties，这个无身食人头的目标，是吞噬一切
Dubbed the Kanontsistonties, this disembodied man-eating head's goal is to consume anything and everything.
男人、女人、孩子、整个村庄，甚至胃药，无所不食
Men, women, children, entire villages, Prylosec, you name it.
据说这些飞天头颅，是那些生前曾食人
These dirigible domes are said to be the cursed souls of ones who have engaged in cannibalism
或犯下其他各种恐怖行径之人的受诅咒灵魂
or other various horrific acts within their lifetime.
因此，他们注定要在世间游荡，承受永不满足的饥饿诅咒
Thus, they are doomed to roam the earth with the curse of insatiable hunger.
这些头颅可能只是纯粹的骷髅
These heads can take the form of just mere skulls,
但有些传说版本将它们描绘成有血有肉的面孔
but some versions of the tale depict them as full-fleshed faces
长着飘逸的长发，要么有羽翼，要么有蝙蝠般的翅膀
with long flowing hair, either with feathered or bat-like wings.
它们的描述让我想起了塞尔达系列里的那些骷髅
Their description reminds me a lot of those skulls from the Zelda franchise,
特别是在《时之笛》里井底的那个巨大家伙
particularly that one giant fella in the bottom of the well in Ocarina of Time.
我扯远了
But I digress.
据说，即使只是谈论它们，也会将它们吸引到某个地区
It is said that even speaking about them attracts them to an area,
因为它们曾降临在那些让其传说流传下去的整个村庄
as they have been known to descend on entire villages who keep their legend alive.
一旦被召唤，这些怪物便开始大肆破坏，撕咬受害者
Once summoned, these monsters begin wreaking havoc, biting and tearing victims apart,
或将他们一口吞下，但因为没有胃，只能立刻再吐出来
or swallowing them in one gulp, only to have to bite them immediately after, since they have no stomach.
它们的速度和巨大的体型，让逃生几乎不可能
Their speed and sheer size makes escape nearly impossible.
就算你像只受惊的小老鼠躲在屋里
Even if you're hiding in a house like a little frightened mouse,
或者吓破了胆藏在井里
or scared as all hell while hidden in a well,
它们也会冲进你的小屋，只为尝一口鲜嫩的小点心
they'll attack your shack for a crack at a tender little snack.
至于如何打败它们，你基本上是没辙了
In terms of defeating them, you're kind of SOL,
因为传说 Kanontsistonties 几乎是不死的
as legends state that the Kanontsistonties is virtually immortal,
因此无法被摧毁，除了一种原始武器
and thus cannot be destroyed, save for one primitive weapon.
火
Fire.
所以，拿出你的打火机和随身携带的身体喷雾，动手吧
So, get out your lighter and your pocket can of body spray and get to it.
真棒
Neat.
好了，这次盘点就到这里
Well, that's all for this list.
如果这些怪物是真的，那可就太可怕了，不是吗
These monsters would be pretty scary if they were real, wouldn't they?
想了解更多神话中的奇珍异兽吗
Want to learn about more mythical critters and creatures?
看看这个视频
Check out this video.
咱们那边见
I'll see you over there.